Guide to the Records of the Leo Baeck Institute London undated, 1907-2008 (bulk 1956-2000) AR 6682
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
Leo Baeck Institute London Records
undated, 1907-2008
bulk 1956-2000
Leo Baeck Institute London
This collection contains records documenting the operation of the Leo Baeck Institute London. The majority of the material relates to the publication of The Leo Baeck Institute Yearbook, journal of the Leo Baeck Institute. It is the pre-eminent journal on central European Jewish history and culture. Also included is a small amount of documentation about the ongoing series of monographs on German-Jewish history, the Schriftenreihe wissenschaftlicher Abhandlungen des Leo Baeck Instituts. The collection also contains administrative documents, such as general and LBI-internal correspondence, meeting minutes, and reports, as well as printed materials clipped and saved by LBI London. It also includes a small but wide-ranging set of archival materials collected by or donated to LBI London.
24 linear feet + one oversized item.
AR 6682
Leo Baeck Institute
Historical Note
The Leo Baeck Institute was founded in 1955 and is named after Leo Baeck, who was the last public representative of the Jews in Nazi Germany. Its aim is to put on record the history and culture of German-speaking Jewry throughout central Europe, from Koenigsberg to Alsace, whose contribution to their countries of origin was immense. The LBI consists of independent centers in New York, Jerusalem, and London. The Wissenschaftliche Arbeitsgemeinschaft, the Verein der Freunde und Foerderer in Frankfurt/Main and the branch of the New York archive at the Jewish Museum in Berlin – all in Germany – contribute to the work of the three centers.
The London Institute is responsible for The Leo Baeck Institute Yearbook, which has appeared annually since 1956. Its articles cover cultural, economic, political, social and religious history, the impact of antisemitism and the Jewish response to it. Its classified bibliography is recognized as being of unique value for researchers and students. Over the years, the London Institute has also produced many symposium volumes and monographs, as well as more than 70 volumes in the Schriftenreihe wissenschaftlicher Abhandlungen des Leo Baeck Instituts. In addition to its publishing activities, the LBI London organizes a broad range of events such as lecture programs and international conferences, both in the UK and abroad, and also funds fellowships.
More information about the history of LBI can be found in Preserving the Legacy of German Jewry: A History of the Leo Baeck Institute 1955-2005(2005).
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains records documenting the operation of the Leo Baeck Institute London. The majority of the material relates to the publication of The Leo Baeck Institute Yearbook, journal of the Leo Baeck Institute. It is the pre-eminent journal on central European Jewish history and culture, featuring the world's most prominent experts in the social, cultural, intellectual and political history of Jews in central Europe after 1789, including the Holocaust. Records in this collection include the Yearbook Binders from 1956 to 2000. These comprise the primary internal record of the editorial work behind each volume, and include extensive correspondence with the authors of the yearbook articles. Other yearbook materials include reviews and administrative documents. The collection also includes a small amount of documentation about the ongoing series of monographs on German-Jewish history, the Schriftenreihe wissenschaftlicher Abhandlungen des Leo Baeck Instituts. Administrative documents reflecting the basic functioning of LBI London include general and LBI-internal correspondence, meeting minutes, and reports. The collection also includes printed materials clipped and saved by LBI London mostly from the 1950s through the 1970s, such as reviews of its publications, German-Jewish subject files, and articles about LBI London itself. The collection also contains a small but wide-ranging series of archival materials collected by or donated to LBI London.
Arrangement
Series I: Leo Baeck Institute Yearbook,undated, 1930s-2000, bulk 1956-2000
Subseries 1: Yearbook Binder,1956-2000
Subseries 2: Additional yearbook correspondence,1955-1999
Subseries 3: Layout work-product,1956-1993
Subseries 4: Reviews,undated, 1957-1984
Subseries 5: Unpublished materials,undated, 1930s-1983, bulk 1960s
Series II: Schriftenreihe,1959-1994
Subseries 1: Publication files,1965-1969
Subseries 2: Reviews,1959-1994
Series III: Administrative,undated, 1951-1996
Subseries 1: Correspondence,undated, 1951-1996
Subseries 2: LBI correspondence,1955-1994, bulk 1977-1994
Subseries 3: Minutes, reports, and organizational documents,undated, 1955-1968
Subseries 4: Various,undated, 1957-1970s
Series IV: Printed Materials,undated, 1923-2004, bulk 1955-1975
Subseries 1: Reviews of German-Jewish publications,undated, 1955-1999, bulk 1957-1975
Subseries 2: LBI London clippings,1955-2004, bulk 1955-1975
Subseries 3: Subject files,undated, 1923-1995, bulk 1956-1972
Series V: Collected Materials,undated, 1907-2008
Series were determined based on record function. The folder and binder titles used by LBI London where maintained, where they existed, and otherwise arranged by function. The primary function of the London center within the Leo Baeck Institute organization is scholarly publication. The first two series are records relating to the Leo Baeck Institute Yearbook and the Schriftenreihe wissenschaftlicher Abhandlungen des Leo Baeck Instituts. Series III contains administrative documentation, primarily correspondence. The fourth series contains printed material, chiefly collections of clippings, while the fifth series includes materials collected by and donated to LBI London.
Related Material
The Library holds many of LBI London's publications, including the Yearbook, the Annual Report, and many of the Schriftenreihe publications.
The Archives holds materials from the yearbook's first editor, Robert Weltsch (AR 7185) as well as a small collection relating to the second editor, Arnold Paucker (AR 3985).
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers. There may be some restrictions on the use of the collection.
Access Information
Readers may access the collection by visiting the Lillian Goldman Reading Room at the Center for Jewish History. We recommend reserving the collection in advance; please visit the LBI Online Catalog and click on the "Request" button.
Separated Material
Books, pamphlets, magazines, and complete newspapers were removed to the LBI library.
The following dissertation abstracts were removed to the LBI Manuscript Collection:
Doron Niederland, "Emigration Patterns of German Jews 1918-1938" (1988) –MS 813
Jacob Toury, "Jewish Political Orientations in 19th-Century Germany (1815-1870)" (1960) –MS 814
Weltsch, Robert; Paucker, Arnold; Grenville, J. A. S. (John Ashley Soames), 1928-; Leo Baeck Institute London; Jews--Germany--Historiography; London (England); Correspondence; Clippings (information artifacts); Manuscripts
Container List
- Series I: Leo Baeck Institute Yearbook, undated, 1930s-2000; bulk 1956-2000; 11.5 linear feet and one oversize item.
  This series contains materials relating to the publication of The Leo Baeck Institute Yearbook, journal of the Leo Baeck Institute. It is the pre-eminent journal on central European Jewish history and culture, featuring the world's most prominent experts in the social, cultural, intellectual and political history of Jews in central Europe after 1789, including the Holocaust.
  The yearbook has been edited by Robert Weltsch (1956-1970), Arnold Paucker (1970-1992), John Grenville (1993-present), and Raphael Gross (2003-present). It has helped shape the study of German-Jewish history throughout its existence. For the first fifteen years, the yearbook primarily published essays by and often about people who had been prominent members of the German-Jewish community. Under Arnold Paucker's editorship, the yearbook moved toward publishing more material by professional historians, as it continues to today. Christhard Hoffmann's essay "An International Forum for German-Jewish Studies: The Year Book of the Leo Baeck Institute," in Preserving the Legacy of German Jewry: A History of the Leo Baeck Institute 1955-2005(2005), provides a brief overview of the yearbook's history.
  Subseries 1, the Yearbook Binders, contains the majority of the material. It comprises the primary internal record of the editorial work behind each volume, and includes extensive correspondence with the authors of the yearbook articles. The second subseries,Additional yearbook correspondence, documents the details of printing and distributing the yearbook, and also contains other administrative correspondence.Layout work-product contains the complete 1976, 1977, and 1993 volumes as annotated typescripts, as well as one folder of draft cover designs for the first volume in 1956. The Reviews subseries consists of clippings from a wide range of publications reviewing the yearbooks.Unpublished materials, primarily manuscripts, are found in the last subseries.
  A key feature of each yearbook is a bibliography of scholarly materials about German Jewry published that year. This series contains very little material about the bibliography.
  This series is divided into five subseries, based on the function of the records. The Yearbook Binders were clearly labeled as such by LBI London, while the remaining four subseries were identified during processing.
  - Subseries 1: Yearbook Binder, 1956-2000; 8 linear feet.
    This subseries is arranged by yearbook volume. The date refers to the year in which a given yearbook was published. However, correspondence with authors often began years before publication, and sometimes continued thereafter. Many of the binders have a small amount of front matter, such as a table of contents and letters of acknowledgment to the authors. Binders with more substantial front matter are noted. The individual binders were arranged in alphabetical order by correspondent. Binders were originally one large unit, but were broken up into folders during processing.
    Each volume of the yearbook has a dedicated binder, which is the primary internal record of the editorial work behind that volume. It contains correspondence with the authors and referees, information about the contributors, and internal notes. There are occasional manuscripts and clippings, and some correspondence with proofreaders, as well as criticism of articles and errors to be corrected. As noted above, the yearbook has been a premier outlet for scholarship on German Jews since its inception; much of the correspondence in this subseries is with leading scholars, and it is often substantive. This subseries contains the Yearbook Binders for volumes I-XLV (1956-2000).
    - YB Binder I, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - YB Binder II, A-K, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - YB Binder II, L-W, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - YB Binder II, Circulars and Notes, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - YB Binder III, A-P, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - YB Binder III, R-W, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - YB Binder III, Circulars and Notes, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - YB Binder IV, B-P, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - YB Binder IV, R-W, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - YB Binder IV, Circulars and Notes, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - YB Binder V, A-D, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - YB Binder V, E-L, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - YB Binder V, M-W, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - YB Binder V, Circulars and Notes, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - YB Binder VI, A-C, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - YB Binder VI, D-S, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - YB Binder VI, Circulars and notes, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - YB Binder VII, A-L, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - YB Binder VII, O-W, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - YB Binder VII, Circulars and notes, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - YB Binder VIII, A-J, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - YB Binder VIII, K-R, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - YB Binder VIII, S-Y, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - YB Binder VIII, Circulars and notes, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - YB Binder IX, A-G, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - YB Binder IX, H, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - YB Binder IX, J-W, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - YB Binder IX, Circulars and notes, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - YB Binder X, A-D, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - YB Binder X, F-J, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - YB Binder X, K-R, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - YB Binder X, S-T, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - YB Binder X, U-Z, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - YB Binder XI, A-K, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - YB Binder XI, L-Z, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - YB Binder XI, Circulars and notes, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - YB Binder XII, A-G, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - YB Binder XII, H-Z, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - YB Binder XIII, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - YB Binder XIV, A-G, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - YB Binder XIV, H-L, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - YB Binder XIV, M-W, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - YB Binder XV, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - YB Binder XVI, A-L, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - YB Binder XVI, M-N, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - YB Binder XVI, S-W, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - YB Binder XVII, A-C, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - YB Binder XVII, D-P, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - YB Binder XVII, R-Z, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - YB Binder XVIII, A-L, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - YB Binder XVIII, P-S, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - YB Binder XIX, A-D, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - YB Binder XIX, F-P, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - YB Binder XIX, R-W, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - YB Binder XX, C-H, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - YB Binder XX, J-P, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - YB Binder XX, R-W, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - YB Binder XXI, C-M, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - YB Binder XXI,R-S, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - YB Binder XXII, A-G, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - YB Binder XXII, H-S, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - YB Binder XXIII, A-K, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - YB Binder XXIII, L-M, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - YB Binder XXIII, P-Z, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - YB Binder XXIV, A-G, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - YB Binder XXIV, K-M, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - YB Binder XXIV, N-W, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - YB Binder XXV, B-C, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - YB Binder XXV, F-P, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - YB Binder XXV, R-Z, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - YB Binder XXVI, A-F, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - YB Binder XXVI, H-R, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - YB Binder XXVI, S-W, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - YB Binder XXVII, B-J, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - YB Binder XXVII, K-W, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - YB Binder XXVII, Z, General, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - YB Binder XXVIII, General, A-B, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - YB Binder XXVIII, C-M, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - YB Binder XXVIII, N-S, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - YB Binder XXVIII, W, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - YB Binder XXIX, A-K, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - YB Binder XXIX, L-M, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - YB Binder XXIX, P-W, General, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - YB Binder XXX, A-H, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - YB Binder XXX, J-L, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - YB Binder XXX, M-R, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - YB Binder XXX, S-W, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - YB Binder XXXI, B-G, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - YB Binder XXXI, H-M, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - YB Binder XXXI, N-R, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - YB Binder XXXI, S-W, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - YB Binder XXXII, B-G, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - YB Binder XXXII, H-R, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - YB Binder XXXII, S-V, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - YB Binder XXXIII, B-G, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - YB Binder XXXIII, H-N, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - YB Binder XXXIII, R-W, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - YB Binder XXXIV, General, A-F, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - YB Binder XXXIV, G-M, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - YB Binder XXXIV, N-S, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - YB Binder XXV, B-L, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - YB Binder XXV, M-R, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - YB Binder XXV, S-Z, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - YB Binder XXXVI, B-F, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - YB Binder XXXVI, G-K, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - YB Binder XXXVI, L-M, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - YB Binder XXXVI, N, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - YB Binder XXXVI, R-W, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - YB Binder XXXVII, A-E, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Two YB 37 binders appear to exist. Each was maintained in original order.
    - YB Binder XXXVII, G-R, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - YB Binder XXXVII, S, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - YB Binder XXXVII, T-W, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - YB Binder XXXVII, Additional Correspondence, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - YB Binder XXXVII, A-F, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - YB Binder XXXVII, G-L, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - YB Binder XXXVII, M-Z, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - YB Binder XXXVIII, B-G, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - YB Binder XXXVIII, J-W, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - YB Binder XXXIX, A-H, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - YB Binder XXXIX, J-M, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - YB Binder XXXIX, N-W, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - YB Binder XL, A-F, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - YB Binder XL, H-M, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - YB Binder XL, P-W, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - YB Binder XLI, A-D, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - YB Binder XLI, E-H, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - YB Binder XLI, J-L, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - YB Binder XLI, M-W, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - YB Binder XLII, A-H, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - YB Binder XLII, J-M, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - YB Binder XLII, N-W, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - YB Binder XLIII, General, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - YB Binder XLIII, Photo Requests, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - YB Binder XLIII, A-C, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - YB Binder XLIII, F-K, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - YB Binder XLIII, M-W, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - YB Binder XLIV, B-F, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - YB Binder XLIV, G-N, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - YB Binder XLIV, P-W, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - YB Binder XLIV, General, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - YB Binder XLV, B-F, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - YB Binder XLV, H-M, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - YB Binder XLV, R-V, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - YB Binder XLV, Internal Correspondence, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 2: Additional yearbook correspondence, 1955-1999; 1.5 linear feet.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    This subseries contains correspondence related to production, publication, and distribution of the yearbook, primarily with the publisher and printer. The most common topics are scheduling, correction of errors, and difficulties with distribution. The subseries also includes some other yearbook-related correspondence, such as rejection letters and a collection of correspondence belonging to editor John Grenville.
    - Autorenvertraege und copyright, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Distribution, 1958-1964 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Distribution, 1969-1973 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Grenville Correspondence, General, 1992-1999 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Grenville Correspondence, A-K, 1992-1999 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Grenville Correspondence, L-W, 1992-1999 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Legal advice re publication contracts, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1963-1973 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Publishing, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Publishing, 1962-1967 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Publishing, 1968-1971 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Publishing, 1972-1981 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Publishing, 1981-1993 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Publishing and Distribution, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Publishing and Distribution, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Publishing and Distribution, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Publishing and Distribution, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Publishing and Distribution, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Rejections, A-F, 1989-1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Rejections, J-M, 1989-1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Rejections, N-W, 1989-1996 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Rejections, A-L, 1996-1999 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Rejections, M-W, 1996-1999 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - YB Index Correspondence, 1980-1995 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 3: Layout work-product, 1956-1993; 1 linear foot.
    This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    This subseries contains the complete 1976, 1977, and 1993 yearbooks in annotated typescript form. This is likely the form in which the yearbook was sent to the printer. There are editorial and layout markings throughout. The subseries also includes one folder of draft designs of title pages for the very first volume of the yearbook.
    - Title page drafts, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - XXI, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - XXI, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - XXI, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - XXI, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - XXI, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - XXI, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - XXII, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - XXII, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - XXII, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - XXII, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - XXXVIII, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - XXXVIII, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - XXXVIII, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - XXXVIII, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - XXXVIII, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - XXXVIII, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - XXXVIII, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Includes 3.5" diskette
  - Subseries 4: Reviews, undated, 1957-1984; 0.3 linear feet and one oversize item.
    This subseries is arranged by yearbook volume.
    The subseries consists of clippings of reviews of the yearbooks. A wide range of publications is represented. Many clippings come from mainstream European (primarily German and English) newspapers and scholarly journals. The American press as well as the worldwide Jewish press are also well-represented.
    - YB I Reviews, 1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - YB I Reviews (scrapbook), 1957 (Box OS140)
    - YB II Reviews, 1958-1960 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - YB III Reviews, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - YB IV Reviews, 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - YB V Reviews, 1961-1965 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - YB VI Reviews, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - YB VII Reviews, 1963-1967 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - YB VIII Reviews, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - YB IX Reviews, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - YB X Reviews, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - YB XI Reviews, 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - YB XII Reviews, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - YB XIII Reviews, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - YB XIV Reviews, 1970-1977 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - YB XV Reviews, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - YB XVI Reviews, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - YB XVII Reviews, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - YB XVIII Reviews, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - YB XIX Reviews, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - YB XX Reviews, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - YB XXI Reviews, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - YB XXII Reviews, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - YB XXIII Reviews, undated (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - YB XXIII-XXXIV Reviews, 1979-1984 (Box 24, Folder 50)
  - Subseries 5: Unpublished materials, undated, 1930s-1983; bulk 1960s; 1.2 linear feet.
    This subseries contains scholarly manuscripts and typescripts of materials that appear to have been submitted for the yearbook but were not published. These materials were found with little contextual information.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by author. Titles are used if the author is unknown.
    - Aufhaeuser, Siegfried interviews, 1967; , 1969 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Callmann, Walter "Der Reichsbund Juedischer Frontsoldaten (RJF)", 1956 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - "Die Deutsche Rechte und die Juden", undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Field, Fred "The Jews of Parchim", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 34)